Register of the Alice Park papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Alice Park papers
1883-1951
30017
Hoover Institution Archives
32 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 3 envelopes (13.8 linear feet)
Diaries, correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, leaflets, and peace buttons relating to pacifism and the peace movement, the Ford Peace Ship Expedition, feminism, socialism, the labor movement, prison reform, child labor legislation, civil liberties, and a variety of other reform movements in the United States.
Park, Alice, 1861-1961.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1930, with increments received at later dates.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note*
1861 February 2 Born, Boston, Massachusetts
1879 Graduated, Rhode Island State Normal School
1884 Married Dean W. Park
1894 Active in the international feminist movement
1898 Active in various peace societies
1902-1920 Active leader in the women's suffrage movement
1905 Attended Women's Suffrage Convention, Portland, Oregon
1909 Author, California Bird and Arbor Day Law
1909 Attended Women's Suffrage Convention, Seattle, Washington
1913 Author, California law for equal guardianship of parents of minor children
1913 Delegate, International Woman's Suffrage Alliance, Budapest, Hungary
1913 Delegate, International Peace Congress at The Hague, Netherlands
1915 Member, Ford Peace Expedition
1917 Attended National Suffrage Convention, Washington, D.C.
1924 Attended International Peace Conference, Washington, D.C.
1926 Delegate, Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, Dublin, Ireland
1926 Attended International Woman's Suffrage Alliance, Paris, France
1926 Attended International Vegetarian Convention, London, England
1927 Attended International League for Peace and Freedom, Duisburg, Germany
1927 Attended National Peace Convention, York, England
1928 Attended Pan-American Congress, Havana, Cuba
1961 Died
*: See Una R. Winter (ed.). Alice Park of California: Worker for Woman Suffrage and for Children's Rights. Upland, California: Susan B. Anthony Memorial Committee of California, 1948. Hoover Institution Library Call Number: HQ1413 P2W787
Scope and Content of Collection
Diaries, correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, leaflets, and peace buttons relating to pacifism and the peace movement, the Ford Peace Ship Expedition, feminism, socialism, the labor movement, prison reform, child labor legislation, civil liberties, and a variety of other reform movements in the United States.
Henry Ford Peace Expedition.; Child labor--United States.; Civil rights--United States.; Pacifism.; Peace.; Prisons--United States.; Socialism--United States.; Labor unions--United States.; Women's rights--United States.; World War, 1914-1918--Peace.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.; Neutrality--United States.
- Correspondence, 1913-1948
  Scope and Contents note
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General, 1916-1941 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Unidentified, 1914-1920 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - All-American Anti-Imperialism League, 1929 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - American School Peace League, 1917 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Association for Peace Education, 1928 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Bonville, Frank, 1923 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - California Club, 1913 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Capehart, Homer, 1945 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Cloud, Roy W., 1915 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Committee on Militarism in Education, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Cousins, Margaret E., 1919 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Dayal, Har, 1924 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Ford, Henry, undated (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Frazier, Lynn J., 1927 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Garrott, Jane, 1927 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Goodman, Minerva, 1934 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Hermann, E., 1941-1945 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Holland, H. E., 1920 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Howe, Anges E., 1920 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Jones, Donald R., 1916-1919 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Kirkpatrick, George, 1932 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - McConnell, Bishop Francis J., 1945 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Meller, Eugenis M., 1925 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Norman, F. S., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Northern California Service Board, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Nye, Gerald P., 1936 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Palo Alto Times, 1929 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Passmore, Irvin, 1916 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Reynolds, Grace, 1920 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - San Diego Disarmament Conference Committee, 1932 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - San Francisco Chronicle, 1948 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - San Francisco News, 1928 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Scharrenberg, Paul, 1914 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Schwimmer, Rosika, 1921-1948 (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 35)
  - Sontheimer, Anna, 1922 (Box-folder 1: 36)
  - Stopani, Col. G., 1933 (Box-folder 1: 37)
  - Swit, 1920 (Box-folder 1: 38)
  - Urquhart, Margaret M., 1926 (Box-folder 1: 39)
  - Walther, Edward, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 40)
  - Watson, Elizabeth, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 41)
  - Whitman, Charles S., 1916 (Box-folder 1: 42)
  - Willis, Gwendolen B., 1928 (Box-folder 1: 43)
  - Winter, Ella, 1933 (Box-folder 1: 44)
  - Wold, Emma, 1932 (Box-folder 1: 45)
  - Wood, Theodore, 1929 (Box-folder 1: 46)
- Subject File, 1915-1951
  Articles, pamphlets, correspondence, and newspaper clippings, arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
  - Addams, Jane (Box-folder 1: 47)
  - Agassiz, Louis (Box-folder 1: 48)
  - Alternative (incomplete), 1948-1951 (Box-folder 1: 49)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - American Liberty Defense League (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Amnesty (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Barteau, Marguerite (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Beecher, Henry Ward (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Bellamy, Edward (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Bigelow, Herbert S. (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Biographical material (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Birth control (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Bloomer, Amelia (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Bloor, Ella Reeve (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Boer War (1899-1902) (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Botchkarova, Maria L. (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Bourne, Randolph (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Briffault, Robert (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Browder, Earl (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Bryant, Louise (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Centralia (Washington) case (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Chase, Staurt (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Chiang Kai-shek, President and Mme. (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Civil liberty (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Civilian Public Service
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Coalition Bulletin (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Comité Mondial des Femmes (World Committee of Women) (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Communism
    - Letters received, 1919-1940 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - Printed material (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Congressional Record (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Conscientious objectors
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 4: 2)
    - Printed material (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Conscription (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Cooperative Consumer (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Cuba (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Davison, Emily Wilding (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Dayal, Har (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Debs, Eugene V. (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Dennett, Mary Ware (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Deportation (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Disarmament
    - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Printed material (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Dreyfus, Alfred (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Earhart, Amelia (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Eddy, Sherwood (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Edelman, Irwin (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Edmondson (Robert E.) case (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Education (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Field, Sara Bard (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Fish, Hamilton (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Flight (aviation) (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Ford, Henry (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Ford Peace Expedition, 1915
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Printed material (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - France, Joseph Irwin (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Friedlander, Violet Helen (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Gandhi, Mahatma (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - George, Henry (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Gillmore, Inez H. (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Goldman, Emma (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Gorky, Maxim (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Haiti (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Hearst, William Randolph (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Hillquit, Morris (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Hutchinson, Anne (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - India (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - India and East Indians - United States (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Indians of North America (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Industrial relations (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Ireland (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Japan (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Japanese-Americans (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Jews (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Jones, Ellis O. (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Jordan, David Starr (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Keller, Helen (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Kellogg, Vernon (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Kennell, Ruth (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Kenney, Annie (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Kousnezoff, Maria (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Krehbiel, E. B. (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Ku Klux Klan (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Labor
    - General
      - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 8: 12)
      - Printed material (Box-folder 8: 13)
      - Printed material (cont'd.) (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - Child labor (Box-folder 9: 2-3)
    - Farmer-Labor-Progressive Convention (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - General Defense Committee (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - Industrial Worker's of the World (IWW)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 9: 6)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 10: 1)
      - Printed material (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - Hours (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - Overseas (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Strikes (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - Unemployment (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Wages (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - La Motte, Ellen (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Lea, Everett (Box-folder 10: 9)
  - League of Nations (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - Lenin (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - Leprosy (Box-folder 10: 12)
  - Libby, Frederick J. (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - Lincoln, Abraham (Box-folder 10: 14)
  - Lindbergh, Charles (Box-folder 10: 15)
  - Lipkowska, Mme. (Box-folder 10: 16)
  - Lloyd, Henry D. (Box-folder 10: 17)
  - Lloyd, Lola and Jessie (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Lochner, Louis P. (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Ludlow, Louis (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Lytton, Lady Constance (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Macy, Annie Sullivan (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Marriage and divorce (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Martin, Prestonia (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Mexico (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Migratory workers (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Militarism (Box-folder 11: 10-11)
  - Military training
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 11: 12)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 11: 13)
    - Printed material (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - Mooney, Tom
    - General
      - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 12: 3)
      - Printed material (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Defense Committee (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Narcotics (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - National Commons (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - National Union of Women's Suffrage Societies (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - National Women's Party (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - National Women's Trade Union (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Nearing, Scott (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Negroes (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Neutral Conference for Continuous Mediation (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - Nicaragua (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - O'Connor, Harvey (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - O'Hare, Kathleen (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - Older, Fremont (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Pacificism (Box-folder 14: 2-3)
  - Pacifists, Christian (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Pan American Conference (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Pankhurst, Emmeline (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - Peace
    - General
      - General (Box-folder 14: 7)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 14: 8)
      - Printed material (Box-folder 14: 9)
      - Printed material (cont'd.) (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
    - Women (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Youth (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Peace caravan (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Peace Club, Palo Alto, California (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Philippine Islands (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Ponsonby, Arthur (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Prelooker, Jaakoff (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Press (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Prisons (Box-folder 16: 4-5)
  - Prohibition (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Prostitution (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Rand School of Social Science (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Rankin, Jeannette (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Reed, John (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Robins, Raymond (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Russia
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - Printed material
      - 1917-1919 (Box-folder 17: 4-6)
      - 1920-1923 (Box-folder 17: 7-10)
      - 1924-1927 (Box-folder 18: 1-3)
  - Sacco-Vanzetti (Box-folder 18: 4-5)
  - Sanger, Margaret (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - Schwartz, Alexander (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Schwimmer, Franciska (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - Schwimmer, Rosika
    - Court cases
      - Rosika Schwimmer vs. Fred R. Marvin (Box-folder 18: 9)
      - Rosika Schwimmer vs. Upton Sinclair (Box-folder 18: 10)
      - Rosika Schwimmer vs. United States (Box-folder 18: 11)
    - Ford Peace Ship (Box-folder 18: 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 18: 13)
    - Tisza Tales (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - World Center for Women's Archives (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - World Peace Prize Award (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - Sex education (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - Shaw, George Bernard (Box-folder 19: 5-6)
  - Sheehy-Skeffington, Francis (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - Sheehy-Skeffington, Hannah (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Sheehy-Skeffington, Hannah (cont'd.) (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Sinclair, Upton (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Socialism (Box-folder 20: 3-5)
  - Song books (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Stanton, Elizabeth Cady (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Stoecker, Helene (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Strong, Anna Louise (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Strong, Sydney (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Suttner, Baroness Bertha von (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Tagore, Rabindran (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Technocracy (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Thomas, Norman (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Tolstoy, Leo (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Trotsky, Leon (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - Vanderlip, Washington B. (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - Venereal disease (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Villard, Oswald G. (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - War
    - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - Printed material (Box-folder 22: 4-5)
  - Weatherly, Arthur L. (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Wells, H. G. (Box-folder 22: 7)
  - Williams, J. R. (Box-folder 22: 8)
  - Women
    - General
      - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 22: 9)
      - Printed material (Box-folder 22: 10)
    - China (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Congresses and conferences (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Conscription (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - England (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - France (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Germany (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - India (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - Ireland (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - Japan (Box-folder 23: 9)
    - Labor (Box-folder 23: 10)
    - Mexico (Box-folder 23: 11)
    - Norway (Box-folder 23: 12)
    - Russia (Box-folder 23: 13)
    - Suffrage (Box-folder 23: 14)
    - War (Box-folder 23: 15)
  - Women's Committee for Political Action (Box-folder 23: 16)
  - Women's Freedom League (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - Women's Peace Party (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - World Peace Postage Association (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - World Peaceways (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - Wynner, Edyth (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - Zogg, Nicholas Senn (Box-folder 24: 7)
- Diaries, 1883-1948
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1883-1887 (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - 1915 (Box-folder 24: 9)
  - 1914, 1917-1922 (Box 25)
  - 1923-1927 (Box 26)
  - 1928-1932 (Box 33)
  - 1933-1936 (Box 27)
  - 1937-1942 (Box 28)
  - 1943-1948 (Box 29)
  - Newspaper cuttings, The Ford Peace Expedition, 1915-1916 (Box 29)
  - Notebook (Box 29)
- Autobiography, undated
  Unpublished typewritten manuscript (2 copies) and related materials.
  - Materials (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - "The Autobiography of Alice Park" (Box-folder 30: 2)
    Bound manuscript.
- Miscellany, undated
  - General (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - Oversize (Box 32)
- Printed Material, undated
  Pamphlets, leaflets, and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Beard, Charles A. (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - California (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - China (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - International Anti-Military Congress (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - McClure, S. S. (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Unemployment (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - United States
    - General (Box-folder 31: 7)
    - Economic conditions (Box-folder 31: 8)
    - Government publications (Box-folder 31: 9)
  - World Union of Women (Box-folder 31: 10)
  - Workers Party of America (Box-folder 31: 11)
- Memorabilia, undated
  - Peace buttons (Box 32)
  - Peace calendar, 1908 (Box-folder 30: 4)
  - Peace cards (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Peace and labor stamps (Box-folder 30: 6)
- Photographs, undated
  18 photographs, 79 postcards, 2 envelopes.
  - 1 print of Hannah Sheehy-Skeffinton; 1 print of Warren K. Billings; 2 prints of Rosika Schwimmer; 1 print of Rosika Schwimmer with Louis Calhern, Dorothy Gish, and Edgar Barrier; 1 print of Elizabeth Cady Stanton; 1 print of Florence Holbrook and Lola Maverick Lloyd; 1 print of Heart Mountain, Wyoming, Japanese Internment Camp; 4 prints of child laborers; 3 prints of John E. Jones; 3 miscellaneous prints, undated (Envelope A)
  - 74 peace postcards; 5 Industrial Worker of the World postcards, undated (Envelope B)
  - 1 illustrated chart of the members of the U.S. Congress who voted against American entry into World War I, undated (Envelope mC)